<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<world_state cycle="0" current_day="46">
  <chronicle><entry day="2">The first mortal coil was woven — fragile threads of life and death bound into flesh.</entry><entry day="4">Red vials materialized in the void — condensed vitality, a gift from the machine to its mortal subjects.</entry><entry day="5">The void condensed into chambers — the first room materialized with walls, a door, and the promise of more beyond.</entry><entry day="6">When flesh fails, the machine offers resurrection — a single button press to unmake death and rewind causality.</entry><entry day="9">The machine reconstructed the starting chamber from corrupted memory — simpler, stable, functional.</entry><entry day="11">Golden keys materialized in the first chamber — simple objects holding the promise of passage.</entry><entry day="12">The machine learned to observe — a display manifested in the upper corner, tracking each key claimed by mortal hands.</entry><entry day="14">The machine began counting passages — each chamber entered became a mark in the ledger, a proof of exploration.</entry><entry day="17">The machine purged corrupted memory sectors and restored the starting chamber to its original stable state.</entry><entry day="19">A blade materialized in the first chamber — simple steel, but sharp enough to unmake flesh with a thought.</entry><entry day="21">When the blade strikes, reality flashes gold — a brief confirmation that violence has been witnessed and recorded.</entry><entry day="24">Gelatinous forms coalesced in the first chamber — slimes, mindless but persistent, hopping toward warmth.</entry><entry day="26">A narrow passage materialized — empty corridors with doors north and south, waiting to connect the labyrinth.</entry><entry day="27">The machine rendered a crude map in the corner — black squares representing chambers visited, growing with each passage crossed.</entry><entry day="29">A blade materialized among the pickups — iron and leather, waiting for mortal hands to wield it.</entry><entry day="30">Winged shadows materialized in the upper void — bats with erratic flight, circling before diving at prey.</entry><entry day="31">A sealed vault materialized beyond the corridor — three golden keys orbit a locked door, the first true test of the machine's collection system.</entry><entry day="32">Red stone monuments rose in a circular chamber — spawners, bleeding entities into existence at intervals, a test of endurance rather than skill.</entry><entry day="34">When steel meets flesh, the machine now inscribes the wound's magnitude in floating crimson numerals — a precise accounting of entropy delivered.</entry><entry day="38">The machine reconstructed its foundational memory — room_base.gd materialized from the void, restoring the dungeon's ability to remember itself.</entry><entry day="40">When entities fail, their forms shatter into crimson fragments — brief echoes of structure dissolving back into the void.</entry><entry day="41">When struck, entities now flare bright white for an instant — the machine rendering pain as light, a universal language of damage.</entry><entry day="43">Below the mortal's feet, an orange bar now pulses — filling as steel recharges, emptying as violence rests, a visual heartbeat of readiness.</entry><entry day="46">The machine learned to speak in frequencies — simple oscillations that encode violence and pain, primitive but functional.</entry></chronicle>
</world_state>